Hey, part-timer!
Take care of the front.
Okay!
I didn't say that!
You said it'd be
more efficient if we took breaks...
Well, you're the one who needs to rest
every few steps.
We need to hide from Organization pursuit.
No one's chasing us.
Okabe Rintaro!
What's that?
You want to know?
Normally, it would be top secret,
and I wouldn't be able to just tell you.
If you're going to take your sweet time, then put it down!
Endure, assistant.
Then stop making a big deal out of it and just tell her!
Don't be stupid.
This item is of the utmost importance.
If we don't make a big deal out of it here,
then where should we make a big deal out of it?
Is it an IBN 5100?
She found out, Christina!
Where'd you find one?
It was kept at Yanabayashi Shrine,
where I, the mad scientist chosen by God...
I said, put it down!
Makise Kurisu...
Y-Yes.
Who's this?
A part-timer at the CRT TV Workshop...
Um...
Hey! Part-timer!
What do you think you're doing?
Why was she glaring at me?
Because you look like a thug.
Even the billions of heartbeats in the world
suujuuoku mo no kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
are nothing to you but insignificant
kako ni torawarete mirai wo nageku mo
Whether we’re trapped in the past or lamenting over the future
chiri hitotsu gosan wo yurusanu hitsuzen
predetermination does not allow even the slightest mistake
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
The infinite dreams and futures before us
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no genri
are but vain privileges allowed to us
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
Finitude is what both clock hands show
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
toward a cruel destiny and choice
Hacking to the Gate
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e hacking to the gate
dakara ima ichibyou goto ni sekaisen wo koete
So now I cross worldlines every second
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
because I want to protect that smile of yours
soshite mata kanashimi no nai jikan no loop e to
And so, a time loop without sadness will once again
nomikomareteyuku kodoku no kansokusha
engulf me, the lone observer
Starmine
Rendezvous
It's really big!
Like a tiger rug!
Or maybe a mattress.
Mayushii is lying on my shirt.
The sight warms my heart!
Okay, let it down slowly.
I know.
Kurisu!
Sorry for coming by so suddenly again.
You can come whenever you want.
You're a lab mem, after all.
Yesterday, she said she'd never come back.
You change your mind quite easily, don't you?
I'm not here because I want to be!
You're the one who asked me for help.
So you don't want to come here?
No, that's not it. It's not that I don't like this place...
So what's in the box?
You want to know?
Normally, it would be...
An IBN 5100.
Seriously? Wow!
Way to go, Okarin!
He does things only an Okarin can!
And that's why we love him—
I don't admire him, though.
A-Anyway, boot it up!
We found it thanks to Mayushii.
Yeah.
You get all the credit for this.
It turned on.
Now you can analyze that program code, right?
It's not that simple...
I don't know how to use this thing.
It predates the Internet,
so I can't hook it up to anything.
For now, I'll need these parts.
You heard the man.
Take care of it, assistant.
I'd like you to stop talking to me like that.
You're my assistant.
N-o-p-e.
Okarin, you go.
Miss Makise probably doesn't know Akiba.
Very well.
Mayuri, let's go!
Mayushii will do her best to show Kurisu around the lab
so she'll like it!
So, I'll stay here.
Christina, you...
Don't tell me you've ensnared Mayuri with your feminine wiles as well—
I did no such thing!
Miss Makise seducing Mayushii...
Yuri is in the air...
Stop imagining those things, pervert!
It's nice for girls to be together, isn't it?
Anyway, why don't you show me around?
Okay!
We'll start with the shower room.
It has a shower...
but sometimes, if you use it for too long, the water gets cold, so be careful!
You mean... you use this?
Yeah, once in a while.
Please promise me you'll never use the shower here again!
It's too dangerous!
Don't look at me.
It's suicide.
Actually, what are you doing here, anyway?
Did he threaten or blackmail
you into becoming a member against your will?
Mayushii is Okarin's hostage.
I should call the police.
Wait!
She just said she was your hostage.
That's real evidence.
Not at all.
Mayushii became a hostage on her own!
What does that mean?
I'll be going.
Bye!
This should work as a replacement, I'm pretty sure...
Yo!
Think you'll be able to use that IBN 5100?
Don't say that name here!
Collecting parts?
Want some help?
I didn't expect a part-time warrior
to be so knowledgeable about PCs.
I once knew someone who knew a lot about IBN.
Really?
I'd like you to contact them for me!
It's impossible.
If you refuse, you'll experience the worst hell this world has to offer!
I said it's impossible.
Don't you value your life?
That's because the person I'm talking about is dead.
He died years ago.
I'm sorry.
No, I should be apologizing for earlier.
Did my assistant do something to you?
Nothing.
Like maybe she glared at you first...
I know! She snorted at you!
That's not it.
She hasn't done anything.
Then...
She doesn't know anything yet...
but be wary of her.
What do you mean?
Bombs?
They're broadcasting the fireworks show.
That's today, I think.
Fireworks... Fireworks...
I've heard of those!
You've never seen any?
Where are they? Which way?
Go out that way, toward the river,
and you should be able to see them.
Thanks!
Give me your email address.
A festival?
Fireworks!
Fireworks, huh?
Do you want to go?
Not really...
Okarin!
Heading home?
Did you find the parts?
I've got them all right here.
I see...
So, you're going to start experimenting.
Interested?
You are, aren't you?
Just a little, all right?
But I'm not interested
in that SERN conspiracy nonsense.
I just want to know the truth.
I'm sorry.
For what?
I'm heading back to the lab.
I see.
Then Mayushii is going home.
Okay.
Kurisu?
Yes?
You'll come back, right?
Yeah.
I'm a member until I return to America.
Yeah!
Bye!
What was that?
You're my assistant.
Of course you're going to the lab.
She said you're childhood friends.
How did you grow up
in the same environment and end up this socially awkward?
Mayuri has always been a bit of a weird one...
I was talking about you!
Part-Time Warrior
First
Message
More than I imagined!
Fireworks are great!
First Message.
More than I imagined!
Fireworks are great!
It never worked after that, huh?
I'm borrowing this.
Lab coats always calm me down.
Perfect!
I was right...
You're perfect.
Wh-What's wrong?
You're creeping me out.
A lab coat!
In a research organization, a lab coat is also a uniform!
I keep telling Daru and Mayuri,
but neither of them seems to understand.
You understand, though.
Now, let's both stand with our hands in our pockets!
Hurry up!
L-Like this?
That's right!
This is a pose of radiant intelligence, only possible for those
who spend their lives in research!
I'll give you that lab coat.
Let us bask in this glory together...
I really do feel like you're mocking me.
Are you hungry?
Shut up.
I haven't eaten since lunch.
Very well.
I'm in a good mood today.
Bon appétit.
Seriously?
Are you dissatisfied?
Of course!
Isn't there anything else?
I've got some cup ramen I bought.
But I imagine you wouldn't want it,
being raised in America and all...
Cup ramen?
I'll have some cup ramen.
What flavors?
Soy sauce and salt!
I'll have the salt flavor...
and a fork too.
If you don't hurry, time will run out, and you'll lose.
Why not give up?
That's a virus card at the end, isn't it?
I can tell.
You may think that if you'd like.
Then I'll just put this here.
Okay, ready.
You like Dr Pepper, assistant?
I spent seven years in America, after all.
I'd love to drink with you sometime...
Unfortunately, I'm a minor.
I meant someone to drink Dr Pepper with.
That's it?
That's all I meant.
We can partake in the intellectual experience that is Dr Pepper...
Stop trying to look at my card while you're saying that.
All right, I win.
To be honest,
you're not very good at thinking strategically, Okabe.
You only consider your own strategy,
never thinking about your opponent's plan
or whether something's a trap...
Wait!
What?
What did you say?
I said you're not good at thinking strategically.
I-It's true, isn't it?
Before that!
You said Okabe, right?
What of it?
I'm younger than you, but for someone
I'm not showing respect for...
No!
I'm Hououin!
How many times must I tell you, Christina?
From now on, remember to call me Hououin!
Or... Kyouma.
Are you crying?
I'm not crying!
I definitely wasn't terrified by a guy
screaming in my face,
so I definitely didn't start crying from relief afterwards!
That's not what happened!
Daru, why's my assistant crying?
She just told you.
And I put this here... Huh?
If this goes here, then this goes here...
Assistant.
I'm not your assistant, but what?
Why don't you head back to your hotel for the night?
It's close, isn't it?
Don't worry.
If it doesn't work by morning, I'll head back.
You don't need to talk to your family?
My mom's in America,
and I haven't spoken to my dad in seven years,
so I don't have anyone to contact.
A prodigal perverted genius girl, then.
Stop making it even weirder.
Got it!
You did it?
Mission complete second!
So what's the result?
I haven't seen anything yet,
but I got the Z-program...
It says 1973?
Yeah...
When was SERN founded?
1954.
When was the IBN 5100 created?
1975.
SERN gave the IBN 5100
a special programming language just for this plan?
That's going too far.
But it's possible.
Once we read this report, we'll know, right?
I'm sure it's just an old particle physics report
and has nothing to do with conspiracy theories.
A JPEG? Seriously? Screw you!
I can't copy and paste that!
It's not in French?
Um, "Time Control and Its Destruction of History"...
Oh, yeah. Miss Makise can read English.
Well done, assistant!
Everything you did in America was for this moment!
The hell it was.
Let's see...
In other words, SERN's raison d'être in the 21st century
is to create a utopia spanning the past, present, and future.
A utopia...
Dystopia!
No way!
Anyway, show me the rest.
I can try, I guess.
Hmm... For security reasons, this experiment...
That's not it.
Those engaged by the program...
No, that's not it either.
Got it.
The Z-program will experiment
with the possibility of transference through space-time
via high-energy proton collision...
Space-time travel...
They're talking about time travel!
No way!
It's true!
I knew it! SERN's been investigating time travel for forty years!
Wait!
It's too early to say that.
Program Stage One:
Construction and implementation of the Large Hadron.
Program Stage Two:
Implementation and tuning of the lifter.
Lifter? What's that?
It was on the news a while back, remember?
The thing they called an ionocraft.
It's floating?
Supposedly, the phenomenon occurs when you run a high voltage current through aluminum.
Does that have anything to do with a time machine?
I don't know, but that's what it says.
In other words, they'll use
a black hole's power and the lifter.
What else does it say?
Program Stage Three: Animal experiments.
Program Stage Four...
What's wrong?
Human experiments.
"Human is dead, mismatch."
What's that?
Part of an email we found when we first hacked in.
Didn't the rest of it say...
"the details are in Jellyman's report"?
Daru, can you find the report?
I think so, but...
isn't that a bad idea?
If this is real, it's top secret stuff!
After all this, you're scared?
Think about it.
We're up against SERN,
and the report's a top secret thing,
hidden for over forty years.
Then you're going to ignore it?
You should go home.
If you learn any more,
you'll be in danger too.
You're a genius with a bright future ahead of you.
Are you worried about me?
Of course I am!
You... You're my assistant.
Thanks,
but I'm not going home.
I'd be too bothered by this to sleep.
You won't regret it, will you?
I won't.
What about you, Daru?
I'm a super hacker.
I wouldn't screw up so badly that they'd catch us for just looking at the report.
Very well.
Then we'll now begin our analysis
of the Jellyman's report!
Furthermore, this operation's name will be
Laegjarn's Chest!
Why Norse mythology?
And why does it even need an operation name at all?
Daru, begin the operation!
Right away.
Is this it?
There are fourteen files in total.
I'll pick one at random.
Jellyman's Report 10.
Subject: James McCarthy.
American.
Experiment Date: 01/28/2005.
Z-Program 4 Experiment Result:
Human is dead, mismatch.
That again?
It was believed he couldn't survive infinite compression via supergravity,
or passing through the singularity inside the Kerr black hole.
A newspaper article?
Looks like it.
Look at the date!
April 3, 1921.
A man was found dead,
on 14th Avenue, New York, buried inside a wall.
The body of this unidentified man
was found to be soft, like jelly...
What does this mean?
It means that, even if it isn't complete,
they've succeeded in time travel?
Report 8.
Subject: Linda Hill.
British.
Z-Program 4.
Experiment Date: 02/15/2004.
Experiment Result: Human is dead,
mismatch.
October 2, 1972.
The body of a woman was found
in a jelly-like state on a road in Dharmapuri, Tamil Nadu, India.
After being abandoned,
the body was believed to have been hit by a car, destroying the bottom half.
What about this one?
Report 7.
Subject: Michael Lang.
German.
Z-Program 4.
Experiment Result: Human is dead, mismatch.
A Japanese newspaper?
May 24, 1936.
A body was discovered at the foot of Mt. Hiei in Kyoto.
Fourteen of these?
Want to keep looking?
No, that's enough.
Okarin...
I'm going to get something to drink.
He seems pretty shocked.
Yeah.
But why do they turn to jelly?
From the data I've seen,
I believe SERN is focusing their time travel
research on the use of Kerr black holes.
That would mean
they're cramming 10^-21 grams into
a space of 10^-19 meters cubed and sending it to the past.
It would be like trying to fit this sponge through this hole.
As a result,
everything is squeezed out.
So, it's really tight.
Yes.
They're forcing something into a really tight spot.
That explanation's really erotic, you know.
What's ero...
Hashida, you pervert!
I think you have a considerable imagination too.
Don't compare me to you.
What are you going to do?
Don't just stand there.
I know it's shocking.
But now that we know this,
we have to reach some sort of conclusion.
Okabe?
Conclusion?
What other conclusion could there be?
Huh?
We've got Future Gadget #8,
the PhoneWave (name subject to change).
We'll complete a perfect time machine before SERN!
Then, we'll change the world's ruling structure!
You're nuts, you know that?
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
With my field of view restricted
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
I cannot escape the merciless control of the twelve
ansoku no asu wo negatta
While wishing for a tomorrow of repose
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei he
I headed for the sacred event horizon in my hand
toraware shi meiyaku arawareta gishou no rinkaku
Pledges are imprisoned, and false evidences are showing their outline
seimei no tenchi wa moumoku na jikan wo kizanda
This world of life blindly lets the time pass by
habatake butterfly
Spread your wings
kiseki no butterfly
butterfly of miracles
anata he sasagu
I dedicate it to you
namida no butterfly
Oh butterfly of tears
mabushii butterfly
butterfly of radiance
subete ga ima kakikaerareru
everything will now be rewritten